Destroyer Yukikaze
We are currently in orbit 200,000 kilometers from Pluto.
Battle stations!
No enemy sighted off the coast of Pluto.
The seas are calm. It's almost scary.
Send up a signal round.
First Fleet
Flagship Kirishima
Signal round sighted from vanguard ship Yukikaze.
"I have entered the operations area."
Spotters report enemy sighted.
Multiple contacts. Starboard, four o'clock.
EM wave restrictions released.
Identify enemy ships.
One Super-Dreadnought Class Warship.
IDENTIFIED
Seven battleships.
Twenty two cruisers.
Multiple destroyers.
All ships to combat positions. 30 to starboard.
Prepare for torpedo exchange.
Starboard!
Distance 7500.
Relative speeds unchanged.
Message from the enemy fleet:
"Attention Earth fleet,
surrender immediately."
How shall we respond?
Tell them: "Nuts."
"Nuts!"
Yes, sir.
Earth fleet responding.
"Nuts."
The Yugiri has sunk.
The Kurama is leaving formation!
Commander!
Not yet.
Enemy ship is in firing range.
Target locked.
Open all gunports!
Fire!
Evasive maneuvers!
The Abukuma and Shimakaze have sunk.
Still no word from the Amaterasu?
No messages received, sir!
The Isokaze has been hit,
and is leaving formation!
Will they really come?
We need to believe.
We've been damaged.
We're leaking cyanide gas.
Damage to starboard deck three.
Engine output is dropping!
Damage control, get those bulkheads down! Hurry!
Wait!
Hang on!
Don't die, kid!
Mom...
Damn it!
We have lost control of our vessel! We are leaving formation!
Our main cannon just isn't big enough!
The enemy has an overwhelming advantage.
This was an ambush?
Turn the ship! Reverse course!
Firefighting teams, hurry!
Keep working! Maintain output!
Watch for plasma leaks!
Chief...
We've got things under control, but at this rate...
I said it'll be all right.
Believe. That man is helming this ship.
Our fleet has suffered eighty percent damage.
Signal from Amaterasu confirmed.
They're on course, at outer space speed.
They will be passing Neptune shortly!
Ten minutes until target reaches Mars!
Send an encoded message to HQ:
"The Stone Door of Heaven is opening."
UN Cosmo Force Far East Sector Headquarters
At 1200, the First Fleet encountered the enemy
380,000 kilometers off the coast of Pluto.
The state of the battle is currently unknown.
A message from Commander Okita of the Kirishima.
"The Stone Door of Heaven is opening," he says.
Everything's going as planned so far.
When will the rendezvous with the target take place?
There's a two-man recovery squad waiting at Arcadia Port on Mars.
Mars, Remains of Arcadia Port
It's been three weeks since we were dropped here.
I wonder if Operation M was a success.
My brother's fighting on Pluto, and I'm just sitting here...
Yes?
Roger.
That's our cue.
Is that it?
Hey, Kodai!
It's an escape pod.
That's it.
Well?
That's a girl?
Looks like it.
She's beautiful...
So this is it?
The Isokaze's been destroyed.
Stay strong!
Fire!
The Uzume has recovered from Amaterasu.
The First Fleet's operation is complete.
Withdraw!
Enemy destroyer approaching quickly from above us!
Sight target.
Gunports one and two, fire!
Confirmed hit. Target destroyed!
All right!
Enemy ship has sunk.
Enemy fleet is reorganizing.
Issue a withdrawal order to all ships.
How many allied ships survived?
Just us and one destroyer.
Whose ship?
Major Kodai's Yukikaze.
Withdrawal signal from the Kirishima.
Withdrawal?
"We will now withdraw. Follow us."
We're leaving the battlefield.
Hard to starboard.
The Yukikaze isn't turning!
What?
Kodai, follow me.
Commander Okita, I'm not going to withdraw.
Kodai!
The Yukikaze will remain on the battlefield and support the Kirishima's withdrawal.
Kodai, we've made many sacrifices, but the operation was a success.
Withdraw!
If we don't do something, Earth's fleet will be destroyed.
Then there will be no one left to protect the Earth.
Kodai!
Commander Okita, you cannot die here.
Earth needs you.
The same thing is true for you!
The same thing, Kodai!
Thank you.
Those words are enough.
Please understand!
Be well. I leave the Earth in your care.
Kodai!
All right then.
Let's go give their base a hard kick.
Cross the waves of the galactic sea
Aim for the fixed star of Centauri
Far beyond the twinkling of the stars
A shining ship of the stars twinkling in space
Set sail! We're leaving port! Raise the anchor!
Hold 'er steady, ahoy!
Everyone, I'm sorry.
Turn the rudder toward the stars!
The Yukikaze has headed into the enemy fleet.
Commander...
Yamanami, maintain course.
Maintain course!
Stay alive, Kodai.
Three Weeks Later
This is the Uzume, requesting permission to dock.
Where's the fleet? Where's my brother's ship?
Here lies a visitor from a distant star
Got it.
Well done.
Hirata, tell me...
What happened to the Yukikaze?
Where's my brother's ship?
The Kirishima has recovered the Amaterasu
and has set a course to Earth.
It cost many lives, but Operation M was a success.
Now the Yamato Plan can actually start, yes?
No, it's just beginning.
There's too much we don't know about our enemy.
All we know is that the enemy are demons called Gamilas.
Now entering Earth orbit.
Two planet bombs. Type MN3.
Collision course. Passing us on the starboard side.
Past satellite orbit. Speed unchanged.
It's useless.
We can't stop it.
We don't have the power to stop it.
It's hard to believe that this ugly red planet is Mother Earth.
Just you wait, devils.
I'll fight as long as I live.
I will never despair.
Even if I'm the last one alive, I will never despair.
2199 AD.
The Earth is on the verge of destruction.
Eight years ago, Earth made first contact with alien life.
Attempts at peace were met with war
and merciless, indiscriminate attacks.
At the second battle of Mars,
we were barely able to stop their direct assault.
But afterwards, they began long-range strikes with planet bombs,
and as a result, humanity was forced
to build underground cities and retreat to them.
The Earth Defense Fleet
has been almost completely destroyed by their powerful military.
Their planet bombs have dried up
the land, polluted the atmosphere,
and killed everything that lives.
And the shadow of death
has started to cover the underground cities, humanity's last fortress.
Passing Through Polluted Zone
The Earth is heading toward destruction.
Scientists say the human race may be extinct within a year.
Enemy Plant Emitting Poison
The enemy has modified the environment of Pluto,
and continues to launch their horrible weapons from there.
Why are the aliens doing that?
Well...
Just like how we terraformed Mars,
they may be trying to change the Earth so they can live here.
Let's Take Back Our Blue Earth
At 16:30 today, a riot broke out in zone 6.
It must be hard, teaching kids while working at HQ.
Sector 702 has been sealed.
Another riot...
Considering the situation...
You're as unemotional as ever.
By the way, I heard the only survivors from the First Fleet were on the Kirishima?
Yeah.
I heard something weird about that.
They said that Operation M was a
diversion to draw the enemy away.
It was classified, so they never told anybody but the brass that they were a decoy.
Hey, you there!
Is that true?
No, it's just something I heard...
You work at headquarters, right?
Where's Commander Okita?
Hey.
Who are you anyway?
Well...
As you can see, we're just back from the battlefield.
Admiral Okita is in the hospital, recovering from his wounds.
Come on, Nanbu.
Yeah...
She looked just like her.
It's your imagination.
Where are you going?
The hospital zone.
You really going to see him?
We were ordered to stay on standby.
I want to know for myself.
Jeez, you're immortal.
I've got the best doctor in space treating me, Dr. Sado.
Aw, I'm not the best... Well, maybe I am.
Where's the capsule?
The techs are looking at it.
It'll be analyzed soon.
No, you can't just come in here!
I need to ask the Admiral something.
Hey!
Is it true that Operation M was a diversion?
Did my brother and the others know?
Be quiet, Kodai.
Captain Hijikata!
Ah, jeez...
I'm sorry. Kodai is my student.
Kodai...
Then you're Mamoru Kodai's...
Mamoru Kodai, captain of the Yukikaze, was my brother.
Mamoru Kodai was a true man.
A great man.
But I was the one who led him to his death.
I'm sorry.
So, what's next?
We'll remain on standby as ordered, what else?
Yeah.
Hey, you two.
I'm sorry about earlier.
Don't worry about it.
But you aren't the only ones to lose relatives in this war.
Just don't forget that.
Anyway, I still can't believe Captain Hijikata was there.
Those two are good friends from Officer School.
Just like you two right now.
Nah, we're not like them.
More importantly, how about it?
Wanna have a drink with me?
Doctor!
This isn't some cheap hooch! It's real sake, the good stuff!
Um, they're gone.
Yeah?
Born July 7th 2178 (age 20)
Seventh Space Tactical Division
Rank: Third Lieutenant
Susumu Kodai
It's me.
Test preparations are ready.
I see.
Yamato Plan Crew List
TOP SECRET
It was worth believing and waiting.
Her words were true.
It's been one year since we moved from the Izumo Plan.
And we're finally at the end of the Yamato Plan.
Where are the crew?
On standby at the designated area.
It was a shame about Kodai.
I've never seen a ship like this before.
You think it's an air defense prototype?
Type-Zero Space Model 52.
AKA the Cosmo Zero.
This is a ship-based craft. It's not used for air defense missions.
You here to sightsee?
We were ordered to stand by here.
I see. Same as me.
Lt. Kato!
Yeah, be right there.
Don't touch it.
Kato...
Saburo Kato. The top ace.
More importantly...
When somebody tells you not to do something...
Yeah.
Enemy mobile squad has broken through our defense line.
Coming down from satellite orbit.
Prepare to intercept!
Hurry!
So they noticed...
The enemy is targeting the sea area off Bonomisaki Cape.
Longitude 30 degrees, 40 minutes.
Good timing.
Yeah. We can use this to shoot them down.
It'll take too long if we have to wait for orders!
Hey!
What are you doing?
That's mine!
You idiots! That's...
Got them!
Is that it?
It looks like a recon plane.
Can you do this?
Of course!
I'm going to avenge my brother.
You're mine.
Hey, they took the weapons off it!
Damn it!
System error?
Hang on!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I guess.
But dressed like this, we won't last until reinforcements get here.
Hey, Kodai!
What's wrong?
What is that?
This is what the enemy was reconning?
No way. It's the scrapped wreckage from a battleship, sunk ages ago.
Yeah.
Episode 1
Messenger of Iscandar
Believe
A star will shine today
Above your head
Even far away
It pours down onto us
The same brilliance
Surely it is the way to return
A small hope to light it up
To the sky you gaze upon
If I pray to eternity for a connection
Even in days of sorrow
Can we meet once again?
The heart knows it is all right
Will it be a mutual promise?
The year is 2199.
The Earth is on the verge of destruction.
Now, humanity's last hope slips past the fangs of the enemy and takes flight.
The name of the ship is the Yamato.
They leave Earth behind, and set a course for unexplored space.
Next time: "Toward a sea of stars."
There are 365 days left before humanity is extinct.